ZAMIL AHAMED

Jailkhana Mor, Narshingdi, Bangladesh + 8801799988859(Office), +8801781099089(personal) ahamedzamil.1155@gmail.com



CAREER OBJECTIVE

To develop a career in a renowned organization that provides structured career advancement and where I will get the opportunities to build up a career and be a part of organization growth utilizing experiences, technical knowledge, hard work and honesty.

EDUCATION

Bangladesh Army University of Science and Technology, (BAUST) Saidpur Cantonment, Nilphamari.

November 2015 – November 2019

Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering.

CGPA:3.54/4.00

Bogura Cantonment Public School and College (Bogura, Bangladesh)

January 2012 – May 2014

Higher Secondary Certificate, Science Background

GPA: 5.0/5.0

Bogura Cantonment Board High School (Bogura, Bangladesh).

September 2009 - December 2011

Secondary School Certificate, Science Background;

GPA: 5.0/5.0

HONRS AND AWARDS

Got academic excellence award in 2^{nd, 4th, 5th}, 6th, 7th, 8th semester final exam respectively

WORK EXPERIENCE

Engineer – Production planning and Procurement (SCM)

SAMSUNG-Fair Electronics Limited, Shibpur, Narsingdi Bangladesh.

Duties and Responsibilities:

22th August 2020 - Present.

- 1. Execute demand and production plan as per demand of BD HQ and marketing team.
- 2. Collaborate working with dimensional teams & SAMSUNG HQ to plan, analyze, and improve production processes.
- 3. Maintain overall production report and submitting daily to HOD and SAMSUNG HQ.
- 4. Input daily production plan on MES based on analyzing production capacity.
- 5. Arrange daily production plan meeting with other production department (IQC, PQC, MM, and Equipment).
- 6. Monitoring incoming raw materials from Korea, Vietnam, materials **GRN**, materials reservation, materials transfer posting, possible production material quantity through **SAP** and **GCSP** systems.
- 7. Making Import Purchase order (PO) and release for consumer electronics materials by SAP system.
- 8. Tracking Letter of credit (LC), Proforma invoice (PI) with Finance and Commercial people.
- 9. Calculating and verify the costing sheet of all import purchase orders per unit cost, gross value, Custom duty (CD), Regulation duty (RD),SD, Bank charge, Insurance, Cost and freight (CNF),Transport, Port damage
- 9. Monitor raw material stock location status and raw materials inventory by SAP system.
- 10. Plan to arrange schedule weakly training for production people topics on MES, SAP, 6S and 5M systems.
- 11. Performed production operation process requirements like (BOM making, BOM upload, material new SAP code, FG codes, version maintaining, routing) in SAP and MES system for new model products before production start.
- 12. Knowledge about SCM operation like INCOTERM, LC, HS code, Performa Invoice (PI), Packing List etc.

Assistant Engineer, Production - Line Leader.

14th March 2020 - 20th August 2020.

Best Tycoon (BD) Enterprise Ltd, Narayanganj.

Responsibilities: Maintain Production line process, ESD equipment maintenance, CI process audit, and 6s audit maintain, EHS audit maintain, material management, MES and ERP operating system.

Duration: 6 months.

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Soft Skills: Technical Skills:

1. Communication. 1. MES. 5. Solid works (Basic).

2. Negotiation. 2. SAP. 6. AutoCAD (Basic).

3. Team work. 3. Microsoft excel (VLOOKUP, HLOOKUP, Pivot table etc.)

4. Time management. 4. Microsoft outlook.

AREA OF INTEREST

1. Planning and Supply chain management.

2. Pharmaceuticals HVAC systems.

3. Pharmaceuticals utility, maintenance.

4. Automobile manufacturing and repair.

LEADERSHIP & EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

1. Bngladesh National Cadet Crops, (BNCC), 3 Mohasthan Battalion.

January 2013-January 2015

Cadet, Cadet number-1343008

2. Department of Mechanical Engineering, (BAUST).

15 November 2017 - 29 November 2019

Class representative.

3. Bd - clean, Khagrachari.

15 August 2019 – 20 December 2020.

General member.

4. Bangladesh Automobile professional association (BAPA), Dhaka zone.

12 March 2021 – Present.

General member.

TRAINNING & WORKSHOP

1. Online Training on - Hybrid Electrical Vehicle system.

1st February 2021 – 10th February 2021.

Conducted by - Bangla Automobile School, "Zihad Uddin Tangime" Asst. manager, Mitsubishi Motors Bangladesh.

2. Fire Fighting rescue and Industrial Safety.

14th September 2020 - 15th September 2020

Bangladesh Fire service and Civil Defense Narshingdi

3. Central locomotive workshop, Bangladesh Railway.

4th November 2018 - 29th November 2018

Industrial training.

4. Bangladesh National Cadet Crops, (BNCC), 3 Mohasthan Battalion. 7 September 2013-13 September 2013 Capsoul Training-02

5. Bangladesh Youth Leadership Center (BYLC) Dhaka, Bangladesh.

10 May 2018 – 12 May 2018

Art and practice leadership (APL) - 20

6. Bangladesh Youth Leadership Center (BYLC) Dhaka.

13 May 2018 - 14May 2018

Office of Professional Development (OPD) Workshop

7. National Mechanical Festival, (KUET) Ignition 2019

26th September 2019–28th September 2019

Participant at automobile Olympiad.

THESIS & PROJECT

"Mechanical Two Degree of Freedom Vibration Analyzer" under the supervisory of Dr. Md. Abdus Salam Akanda, Associate Professor, Department of Mechanical Engineering, Bangladesh University Of Engineering And Technology (BUET), Dhaka Bangladesh.

CONFERENCE PAPER

"Recycling and Reusing Of Lead from Lead Acid Battery" ISBN: 978-984-34-6151-3, at Waste Safe 2019, 6th international Conference paper on integrated solid waste & faecal sludge management in South- Asian countries, 23-24 February 2019, in Khulna University of Engineering and Technology (KUET), Khulna Bangladesh.

LANGUAGES

Bangla (native); English (advanced).

REFERENCES

Dr. - Ing. Irfan Ahmed.

Assistant Professor.

Head of the Department, Mechanical Engineering.

Bangladesh Army University of Science and Technology (BAUST), Saidpur Cantonment.

Mobile: +8801769675564 (off).

Email: headme@baust.edu.bd (Off), irfan ahmed@baust.edu.bd

Md. Shamim Hossain.

Manager, Supply Chain management (SCM) department SAMSUNG – Fair electronics Ltd, Narsingdi, Dhaka Bangladesh.

Mob no: +8801777702226.

Email: Shamim.hossain@fel.com.bd

DECLEARATION

I am Zamil Ahamed hereby declare that the information provided in the resume is true and correct to the best of my knowledge.